Oy! What’s happened here.
- Sand!
- Sabotage!
- Wreckers!
- Deliberate!
- What's at the back of it?
- Who did it?
I know how the law stands.
You broke a contract, therefore you broke the law.
But it’s everywhere.
Look at the street.
I pay my money to look at the pictures.
Just a song at twilight ...
When the lights are low.
- If I want to sit in the dark, I can do it at home.
- Yes.  – Yes.  - Yes.
I think it’s a blinking shame robbing
the poor people like that.
We got to have our money back.
It’s an act of providence,
like an earthquake or a thunderbolt.
- Or a baby.
- Would you kindly not interfere?
- We got to have our money back.
- So sorry I’m late, Mrs Verloc.
But I had a heck of a time trying
to eat my egg on toast in the dark.
Half of it’s in my ear now.
They want their money back.
We can’t afford it.
I do wish Mr Verloc would come.
Rotten lady, I can’t even see the movie!
- They’re getting nasty.
- Nasty? Leave them to me.
Hey you, what’s all this about?
Lend me a flashlight please.
Thank you.
Is it our fault if the light fails?
Supposing you were a policeman,
got hit over the nut ...
... do you think the government would ask
for their money back?
I paid for my seat ...
Yes, and what about the one you
put your feet on?
- Karl, when did you get home?
- I haven't been out.
You weren’t in 20 minutes ago.
I came and called up the stairs.
I was asleep. Why are you shining that
torch on me.
Can’t you switch on the light or something?
We can’t. It’s failed.
What? The fuse gone down?
No, it's everywhere, in the streets and the tram.
And the audience downstairs wants their money back.
They’re making a terrible row about it.
Well, give it back.
We ... we can’t possibly afford it.
Oh yes we can.
You must be crazy.
It’ll clear us right out.
You’re always saying we don’t cover expenses.
That’s alright. It doesn’t pay
to antagonise the public.
I’ve got some money coming in.
Go on.
Well, it’s for you to say.
If we’re going to be generous,
let's do it properly.
Come on downstairs and make a
speech about it.
No no, they’re used to you.
You do it.
Alright. I still think you're crazy.
It’s an act of God, I tell you.
And what do you call an act of God?
I call your face one, and you won’t
get your money back on that.
Now if a plane were to come along and
drop a bomb on you.
That would be an ‘unfriendly act’
within the meaning of the act.
But if the juice dries up of its own accord ...
... that’s an act of providence.
As laid down in the Act of
William the Fourth, where an act is ...
... defined as any activity actuated
by actual actions.
No wonder the blinking lights went out.
It's a moot point.
- I’ll moot point ‘em. Make ‘em pay!
- That’s right ma’am!
- Yes.
- We want our money back!
And how are you going to get it?  Apply sanctions?
Are you familiar with the details of the covenant?
If you’d studied Article 257, paragraph 24,
line 6, section B, it says definitely "No".
Yes, you didn’t know that did you?
You’re all ignorant.
Now if you take my advice you go off home,
because there’s nothing doing here.
- Now go on. Get off.
- What do you think you’re doing.
- Just lending a hand.
- I thought I told you not to interfere.
I’ve been delivering a little counter-attack.
Look, they’re on the run.
Well, they can come right back.
Listen, ladies and gentlemen,
you're going to get your money back.
- Don’t give in now. I’ll stand by you.
- Oh before you go stand by your apple stall.
Ladies and gentlemen, I’ve been speaking
with Mr. Verloc.
And since you are all regular patrons
and good friends ...
- ... he’s going to let you have your money back.
- There’ll be no money back, I tell you.
- Go on. Get off.
- Please, don’t pay any attention to him.
Actually, you’re crazy.
I had it all fixed.
Will you mind your own business.
Of all the obstinate people ...
If you don’t go away, I’ll call the police.
Renee, start refunding the patrons
their money ...
Oh hey, none of that, you haven’t
been here before. Hop it.
Thank you for your trouble.
I’m sure you meant well.
Not at all. I like trouble.
- How many?
- Two seats, please.
- Two shillings, please.
Two shillings? Right.
- Wait your change please. How many?
- One, please.
- How many?   Oh.
- No, thanks.
The vegetables is all ready for dishing up.
Please tell Mrs Verloc, Miss.
Oh there you are ma’am. I’ve got
to hurry home now, because ...
... me husband’s having trouble
with his kidneys again ...
... and I can’t leave him for long.
Your young brother’s looking after them.
- What, the kidneys?
- No, the vegetables.
Oh Stevie! Have you done all this
by yourself?
Oh come on, don't be so modest.
Well, we didn’t have to pay them back
their money, after all.
Always that woman Mrs. Jones manages
to make the cabbage brown.
I’m always telling her
you like them green.
I’ll make you a salad.
Stevie run next door and get
a nice big head of lettuce.
Long or round? I like long best.
Whichever’s freshest. Tell them to charge it.
We very nearly wouldn’t have been
able to afford that ...
... if we’d paid them back.
You didn’t seem very interested
when I told you.
I mean, why were you so keen
to pay them back at all?
No, it’s not that, only anything for quiet.
I don’t like attention being
drawn to us like that.
Good evening, Mrs Verloc forgive me
for butting into your private affairs ...
... but this bright specimen didn’t
appear to know whether he wanted ...
... long, round, square or oblong lettuce.
So I brought a selection.
I distinctly said long ones, you know I did!
- Did you?  I thought you said long ones.
- I said long ones!
Oh, good evening, Mr. Verloc. So you came
home just in time to see the trouble, eh?
- Me?  I’ve been in all the afternoon.
- But I could have sworn ...
- I saw you come in just about ...
- Well you were wrong.
I didn’t know anything about it until
you woke me, did I?
No. He was lying down upstairs.
I had to call him.
Sorry. My mistake, I suppose.
Well here we are ...
I thought someone was committing a murder.
Someone probably is ... on the screen there.
Stevie hop on a chair and fix that fan light.
Look out George Arliss doesn’t bite you, Steve.
Well, goodnight all.
Do you mind if I pop off early tonight, guv?
- OK, Ted
- Thank you.
Good night boys.
That fellow seems to get off
whenever he likes.
Alright, we’ll put someone onto that.
So Sergeant, you saw what
happened tonight?
- Yes sir.
- Anything your end.
I’m not certain, but I could have sworn
I saw Verloc ...
... come back in the middle of it all.
Later, when I challenged him,
he said he’d never been out at all.
- His wife confirmed it.
- Naturally.
She would, if she’s in it.
You better find some way of talking to her.
Now listen Spencer, the Home Office have ...
... been on and they’re scared something
worse than tonight’s job may happen.
What the idea, sir? What’s the point of
all this wrecking?
Making trouble at home to take our minds
off what’s going on abroad.
Same as in a crowd, one man
treads on your toe ...
... and while you’re arguing with him,
his pal picks your pocket.
Who’s behind it?
Ah, they’re the people, you and I will never catch.
It’s the men they employ that we’re after.
- Don’t you know that’s very dangerous?
- What?
Leaving the stuff like that lying about.
Supposing you or me was to break
our leg on that.
You’d be very pleased with yourself,
I suppose.
That would depend whether it was
your leg or mine.
Can’t tempt you, I suppose?
Oranges ...
... very nice today. Good for the feet.
Hello guv. Going to the pictures?
As a matter of fact, I’m off to a trade show.
Well, pick us a good one then ...
you know plenty of murders.
Hmpf. This love stuff makes me sick.
Hmm? The women like it though.
He’s just going!
Well then, tell him not to come back too late,
because we’re going out.
I’m to tell you not to come too late.
I’ll be back as soon as I can.
Penny pineapples. Pineapples a penny.
What’s them bubbles, Dad?
The fish got hiccups?
You’d have hiccups, if you had to live on ant’s eggs.
- They’re funny looking things.
- Yes, they’re funny looking things.
It’ll take three like that
to make soup for ...
... the Lord Mayor’s banquet next Saturday.
Think of that. They say it’s digestable.
There’s a thing with a moustache.
I hope you’re satisfied with
last night’s show.
It wasn’t as easy as it looked.
- I had to spend money, too.
- No doubt.
A neat job though.
The sort of thing to make people sit up.
I think you’ll agree
I’ve earned my money.
I hope you didn’t mind my asking
for it in pound notes.
You made London laugh.
When one sets out to put the fear of death
into people, it is not helpful to make them laugh.
We are not comedians.
- It’s not my fault if they’re such fools.
- Londoners are not fools.
They laughed because they realised
what happened last night was laughable.
They had a right to laugh ... this time.
- What do you mean?
- Mr Verloc, you will be paid ...
... your money when you’ve earned it.
I don’t follow.
My dear Verloc, I once read a sign
in Piccadilly Circus ...
... calling it "the centre of the world."
I think you better pay a visit there
in a couple of days time
... leave a small parcel in the cloakroom
of the underground station.
What sort of a parcel?
Oh, I don’t know ...
Let’s say a parcel of fireworks.
I couldn’t.
I’m not going to be connected with
anything that means loss of life.
You’ll have to get somebody else.
I won’t touch it.
Very well then, Mr Verloc, if you think
you're so well off ...
You know I’m not. You know my position.
Alright then, you’ll be paid your money when ...
When you feel that you’re so fussy
about doing it yourself ...
... surely you have some kind friends
who would help you.
Now don’t be silly.
Go and see this man ...
He’s a very nice old gentleman,
who makes lovely fireworks.
I’ll try and see him.
Don’t forget the date. Saturday next.
Lord Mayor’s show day. Lots of people.
Do you want me to come and report?
Thanks, no.
If your report itself is loud enough,
it won’t be necessary.
Which is the way out, please?
Thank you.
This bivalve’s rate of fertility is extremely high.
After laying a million eggs ...
- ... the female oyster changes her sex.
- Hmpf. I don’t blame her.
- Excuse me, can I help you?
- Yes. Thank you.
Isn’t it fat.
You’d be fat too, if you were fed
corn and bits of bread all day long.
- Why if it isn’t Stevie and Mrs Verloc!
- Oh it’s Ted! Look. Ted.
- Yes, it always is.
- Fat, isn’t it? Ought to eat more fruit, eh?
- You and your fruit! That’s our lunch today.
- Why is that all? How about a nice ...
... juicy steak with me? What about it?
- I’m all for it.
- Stevie!
- Good, where shall we go?
- I’d like to go to Simpsons.
Well, I know Uncle’s been there once.
Don’t be silly, Stevie, we going
to the corner house or a tea shop.
Oh don’t be too hard, Mrs V.
Let’s make it Simpsons.
Come on.
- Have you ever been here before?
- No never.
Stevie look what you’re doing
you are pulling the table.
I saw a picture once, where a chap
snatched the table cloth ...
... off the table and left everything
standing on it.
- You ought to try that at home one day.
- He did.
- All this is very expensive, isn’t it?
- Yes, it looks like it doesn’t it?
- I’ve got a pound note, if you want it.
- It’s alright.
Now Steve, putting aside the steak
for a moment, we have here before us: ...
... oysters, caviar, smoked salmon,
fried, grilled or boiled sole ...
- I’ll have ...
- ... roast saddle of mutton, Kentish chicken pudding ...
... boiled silverside, roast sirloin,
chopped steak, grilled kidneys or roast duck.
I think, Stevie would like a nice
poached egg on toast ...
... and I’ll have a mixed salad.
Here, drink this. Poached egg here at Simpsons?
Why that’s enough to make ...
... the roast beef turn in its gravy.
Three bullocks roasted whole,
and a cup of coffee.
Sirloin to number 8.
When did you come over from America?
About a year ago. Business wasn’t too good
over there.
That’s funny! People used to go over
to the States because ...
... business wasn’t too good over here.
How are things working out now?
- Not too good, mmm?
- Not terribly.
Thought I hadn’t noticed you turning people away.
It’s hard to make a one man business
pay these days ...
... unless you run a sideline.
Has Mr Verloc a sideline?
No, we’re all quite satisfied
with things as they are.
Just one happy little family.
Mr Verloc is very kind to Stevie.
And that means a lot to Stevie’s sister?
It means everything.
- Here we are!
- Good morning, sir.
No fat for you as usual.
You see, I don’t forget.
Haven’t seen you for a long time.
- Do I look as though I don’t like fat?
- What the big idea?
- What idea?
- First, pretending you hadn’t been here before ...
... second, affording to come here on your salary.
That’s what everyone would like to know.
There’s a mystery about me ...
Come to think of it, there’s a mystery about
most people. Haven’t you got some terrible secret?
Never mind about that.
What goes on after hours in that cinema of yours?
Deeds of darkness.
Does your husband go on mysterious journeys?
- He does, wearing false whiskers.
- Ah ha! That means there’s another woman in his life.
- What’s the joke?
- You ought to know him.
He is the kindness, most harmless,
home-loving being.
Well.
What luck with Mrs Verloc?
- She knows nothing, sir. Nothing at all.
- What makes you think so?
She has a straight answer for everything.
Besides, her manner.
Pretty woman?
- What’s that got to do with it?
- Oh I know.
I’m too tender hearted myself,
especially where women are concerned.
- What about Verloc?
- I’m not certain, but if he is ...
... mixed up in this,
he’s not giving himself away.
I’m not so sure about that.
- Your assistant, um what ...
- Hollingshead.
Hollingshead was signalled by you
this morning to follow this man.
- Yes sir.
- Well just reach me that paper, will you.
This is his report. Telephoned from
a call box about 10minutes ago.
Verloc went to the zoo aquarium evidently
by appointment ...
... and met a certain foreign individual,
who handed him a paper.
He then proceeded to 465 Liverpool Rd, Islington,
which is a bird shop.
I’m waiting for him to come out and will
report again later on.
- Islington?
- Exactly. Doesn’t mean much to me, either.
But, I can’t understand, madam, one of my best songbirds.
It sang all day before you purchased it.
Perhaps in a few days, it will settle down.
Nothing will make it settle down. I’ve tried all ways:
Whistling to it, clapping me hands, frying bacon.
No use. It just sits there and makes me look silly.
- It’s not the bird’s fault, I assure you madam.
- Isn’t it?
I’ll have my 2 and 9, please,
and there's your bird back.
- I want a canary for company.
- Perhaps I can make him sing.
- There now.
- Are you sure, it was him?
Listen again.
- I see his beak open.
- Of course you did.
There’s a good boy. Now don’t forget, plenty
of watercress, and you must whistle to him.
Me whistle? Perhaps you’d like me to sit
in the cage and him do the housework.
Yes of course, you want something from
my other department. Don’t you?
Mmm-hmm? This way.
My daughter.
Much better than having a stranger doing for you.
Strangers are too inquisitive, you know.
Now, where’s my key?
How very careless! She oughtn’t to let
the child play out here.
Very dangerous. There you are: no father-
no discipline. What can you expect?
- The little girl’s father’s dead?
- I don’t know.
Might be. I don’t know.
Nobody knows.
My daughter would like to know too.
But there you are.
It’s her cross, and she must bear it.
We all have our cross to bear.
- Everything there look pretty harmless.
- You are right, my friend.
But if I were mix, say, a little tomato sauce
with some strawberry jam, then ...
I gather from our mutual friend that Saturday
is the day and the hour 1:45.
How do I start the mechanism?
Oh you leave that to me. By the time you receive it,
everything will have been set in motion.
You seem a little nervous. Don’t be afraid.
Say to yourself, there is one man who envies you.
- Envies me?
- I’ve been a fighter always until now.
But alas, I’m no longer wanted in the frontline.
I must keep the fighters supplied ...
... but I would rather be in your shoes.
My dear! Just look here!
Yes yes, perhaps you’re right.
I must have put it there myself.
There there. No harm done.
Well, I think everything is quite clear.
Slap me hard!
Granddad’s been very naughty.
- Look there! What’s he doing?
- He might be watching me. Why not?
They probably know too much already.
They’ll raid you one day.
I shall give them a nice warm welcome,
if they do.
He didn’t see me.
On Saturday without fail, sir.  Two canaries in a
nice cage with a very deep tray.
Don’t forget, Saturday at 1:45.
Good day, sir, good day.
That child again ...
- And now, sir?
- I want a nice singing canary.
A canary, you say. My dear little birds
at £1/6s themselves ...
Of course, I realise he wasn’t really
a greengrocer’s assistant at all.
I mean a greengrocer’s assistant can hardly
afford lunch at Simpson’s can he?
He’s really quite well off, and
he's there to learn the business.
It’s one of a big chain, that shop.
If you ask me, I believe ...
... he’s the son of the man who owns them.
How would you like a job selling fruit, Stevie?
I wouldn’t mind with Ted.
He makes it all sound fun.
Wouldn’t it be grand to have steak
whenever you like.
- Crumbs, I’d have it three times a day.
- You’d soon get sick of it.
Bet I wouldn’t. Don’t see how you could
get sick of things you eat.
- Except poached eggs.
- What’s the matter with poached eggs?
I think they’re the worst things in
the world. I bet Ted doesn’t eat them.
- Well, sure he does.
- I bet he doesn’t.
They’re beneath his dignity.
- I don’t think Ted’s so terribly dignified.
- Well, he’s too dignified to eat eggs.
- Hey, I’ve seen it bunching up.
- Oh now, it’s alright.
Do you think Ted will come with us and sail it?
- He might, if you ask him.
- He’s more likely to, if you ask him.
Sailing boats is fun. I like it. But Ted
knows about all sorts of things ...
... gangsters and burglars and everything.
- How does he know?
- He reads about them. He says, gangsters are ...
... not nearly so frightening as you think.
Some of them are quite ordinary looking ...
... like you and me and Mr Verloc.
Perhaps he’s right.
After all if gangsters looked like gangsters,
the police would soon get after them.
Wouldn’t they, I mean.
Six penny, please.
Thank you.
- Is Mr. Verloc in?
- Was he expecting you?
- Yes.
- Do you know your way through?
- Yes, I think so ... Thank you.
- Pass one, Jack.
- I have an appointment with Mr Verloc.
- Do you know your way through?
- No.
- You go right through the theatre.
- Pass one, Jack.
- Thank you.
- Apples a pound there. Apples a pound there.
- Lady there, Ted.
- A pound of those apples, please.
- I have to slip away in a minute.
Maybe, I won’t be bothering you anymore again
after tonight.
Thank you.
Keep an eye, Jim, will you.
One balcony, please.
Pass one, Jack.
[Movie] I’m glad you found this.
It’s the most important of the lot.
[Movie] - I’ll burn it too.
- Allow me.  – Oh thank you.
[Movie] Well, all out for Waterloo and home.
[Movie] Oh!
- Hello Ted, where are you going?
- Just going to have a word with Mr Verloc, sport.
- Oh, he doesn’t talk through loud speakers.
- That’s what’s in there?
There’s only the screen – not much to look at.
Where does that lead to?
- To our front-room. You remember when it fell open.
- I’ll give old Mr V a surprise.
[Movie] - Where’s the sound?
- Come out of that.
[Movie] – Find you nephew.
- How are you?
[Movie] Oh don’t diddle about.
That’s no good. Leave it to me.
[Movie] I’ll get it out of him.
[Movie] - Don’t diddle that to me.
- Well, don’t you talk like that to me.
[Movie] Remember, I’m your uncle.
Not at all. I’m only too glad to pay what
the job’s worth.
Well, I don’t see anything against it.
I’ll call in tomorrow about 11 o’clock.
And afterwards ...
I’ll settle with you, when you’ve
done the job.
Of course, if the Arsenal lose to Birmingham
on Saturday, I shan’t be so pleased.
- Arsenal?  I don’t follow.
- No. I know you don’t follow Arsenal ...
... but they’re a good bet, believe me.
Don’t forget that I filled in about 10 coupons.
Stan here did about 15 bob.
So I’d better ...
Why, I know him.
What were you doing up there?
- Who is he?
- Well, he’s from the grocery next door.
- I know him, alright, but ...
- What happened?
I was showing Ted the back of the screen
and the loud speakers.
Wasn’t that alright?
I hope I didn’t hurt you.
You never know, you know.
Well, Mr Verloc, no harm done I hope.
I must be getting back to shade
of the old apple tree.
Sorry.
Good night all. Good night.
That was Detective Sergeant Spencer
of Scotland Yard.
- But who’s he after?
- You’re having us on.
- But what are we going to do about it?
- But, he’s connected with the ...
... fruit store, next door, I tell you.
Spencer got me my last stretch. The one
I’m on licence from now.
- What are we going to do about it?
- One thing. This job is: off, out, finished.
- We go quick from here and scatter!
- And keep scattered. And if he comes here again ...
... tell him you don’t know where we live.
Say: we’ve gone abroad, anything you like.
Yesterday, at Simpsons, when you had
lunch with that fellow ...
With Ted, you mean?
Remember what he said to you. Did he ask
you any questions about yourself? About me?
None that I can think of.
Why?
Because he’s a detective from Scotland Yard.
That’s why. Spying on us, on me, through you.
But why should he?
What is there to find out?
I’m alright. It must be one of those fellows
who came here tonight ...
But you said, he was spying on you.
No, not me. This place I’m in.
But, if he has anything against anybody
why didn’t he come straight to you. You’d help him.
- I’ll talk to Mr detective Ted.
- No no, I’ll speak to him myself.
- Come and clean all that.
- Right-ho governor.
- Where’s Ted?
- Gone.
- Has he gone to Scotland Yard?
- I’m sorry Mr Verloc. Of course, I didn’t ...
... like the idea, but I couldn’t refuse.
It was official.
But why? What’s wrong.
- Did they say what it’s about?
- Not so far as I know.
You must have been showing some funny
sort of films, I dare say.
You know, perhaps a bit too hot.
Was he there?
Post.
I was trying to get hold of him since first thing
this morning.
- Wasn’t there anybody there to answer?
- No.
Well it’s too late to stop him now.
He’s gone out with an order.
Alright. Alright.
An old man just left this.
I thought he must have made a mistake.
No, that’s alright.
It’s only a pair of birds
for Stevie. I was just phoning about it.
You are terribly good to him.
Not to you?
You’re good to him. You’re good to me.
You know that.
Yes, I know.
- What made you think of it?
- Oh, someone made the suggestion.
Go and call him, will you.
Stevie!
What are you doing up there?
- There’s a surprise for you inside.
- What is it?
Go and see.
There was no one on the door.
Forgive me for busting in like this.
We’re getting used to it. I’m afraid
we’ve nothing showing at this early hour.
I’m sorry Mrs Verloc, but I’m here on business.
Same business as last night?
- Mrs Verloc, there’s nothing personal in all this.
- Isn’t there?
You had us fooled alright, trying to make
Stevie and me think you were a friend.
- Do you think I enjoyed it?
- Then why did ...
Listen, I asked to be taken off this job
this morning. You can guess why.
But it’s not as easy as that.
In my job, you have to do as you’re told.
Well, what have you been told?
Is it about the men who came here last night.
My husband has nothing to do with it.
You’ve got to realise that. Speaking their
own business about the cinema.
That’s just it, you’ve no idea what their business was.
Whatever it was, I’m sure my husband hasn’t
done anything wrong.
I hope you’re right.
Why do you say it like that?
Because we believe there’s something going on here
connected with sabotage.
- Sabot ...?
- That blackout the other night do you remember?
My husband hasn’t anything to do with sabotage.
He told me that night, he’d been in all evening.
That wasn’t true.
I saw him come back with my own eyes.
- I don’t believe you.
- You’re making things very difficult for me.
I afraid I’ve go to ask you a lot of questions.
Now about those men ...
But I’ve told you before, he’s the most harmless person
in the whole world.
He wouldn’t do anything to ...
Did these men arrive together or one by one?
Did you recognise any of them?
Are you quite certain you didn’t know
one of them, yesterday.
Stevie!
- They’re beauties. Which one’s the hen?
- I think you’ll have to wait ...
... until one of them lays an egg.
Wouldn’t it fool everybody, if one day the gent
laid an egg. Gosh, wouldn’t that be funny.
You are right.
Oh, by the way, has that spool reel gone over
to the Canterbury yet?
Well, there’s plenty of time.
Mmmm. I was just wondering, maybe you could take it
along now, because ...
... there’s another little job I want doing at the
same time. You know, kill two birds with one stone.
- Not my birds!
- No no. They’ll be here when you come back.
No it’s ah ... that ah ... projector gadget
that wants seeing to.
Harris out at Watford, says he’ll do it
cheaper than they will in town.
But he can’t come right over here and fetch it
so what they do is this ...
You leave it in the cloakroom
of Piccadilly Circus...
... and Harris picks it up at half past one.
But can he get it without the ticket?
Oh that’s alright, you leave the ticket with the man.
Harris knows me, we’ve done this before.
- You better get along now.
- Oh, there’s no hurry.
- You’ll have to walk all the way.
- Walk? What for?
You know you can’t take film tins
in public vehicles.
Oh yes, I forgot.
You needn’t tell your sister that you’re
going as far as Piccadilly.
You know what she is. Always thinking
you are going to get run over.
Oh, she needn’t worry.
Heads, I wash: tails, I don’t.
Tails it is!
For God’s sake, why don’t you go?
I mean, hurry up you might be late.
Don’t forget, it’s got to be there
by 1:30 at the latest.
- Hello Steve, what have you got there?
- I’m taking a two-reeler over to the Canterbury.
Hmm “Bartholomew the Strangler”.
That sounds a juicy one. Have you seen it?
- Fourteen times.
- Quite a wrench parting from it.
- Well, so long Bartholomew.
- So long.
- Careful of the crossings.
- I can look after myself, can’t I?
- Oh Steve, is Mr Verloc in?
- Yes, I just left him.
I’m afraid I’ve had to impose on you, Mr Verloc.
I couldn’t afford to let you in on this.
Now, I can put my cards on the table.
I’ve come here to ask your help,
nothing more.
I see.
About those men who were here the other night ...
... when I dropped in myself.
I’ve been instructed to get a little information
about them. We’d be very grateful, if you’d help us.
Well, any help I can give them of course ...
About yourself, Mr Verloc ...
When did you first come to this country?
- Can I get you a drink or something?
- Not now, thanks.
We’ll I’ve got to think now, let’s see ...
Perhaps, it would be better if you put it
down on paper. Just a formality.
Would you find a pen and ink. We could start
right away, you know “I, Carl Anton Verloc ...”
Now, ladies and gentlemen.
I want to ask you a question.
Now let me give you just a little demonstration.
- What is it, causes teeth to fall out?
- Why, a punch in the jaw!
Process of decay, inevitable in all
human organisms.
But decay can be arrested, instantaneously arrested.
And by what?
- A copper.
- Yes, exactly. But ...
... if I may say so, by rather more
than one copper, by a few coppers.
I have here in my hand, a tube of that remarkable
preparation, Salvodent,...
... derived from two Greek words “Salvo" - no more;
and "dent" – toothache....
Sixpence a small tube, and a shilling for
the large tube, containing four times as much.
Now if somebody ...
Ah! I see here a young gentleman ...
... who will I’m sure be happy to assist me.
- No, I wouldn’t.
- Yes, you would. Come on, bung him up.
- In the chair, sir, if you don’t mind.
- But I ...
- Allow me to relieve you of this toffee, eh.
- It isn’t toffee and I ...
Alright, alright, alright.
Stay where you are. Don’t get excited.
Now then, here we are. The first thing to do
is take the tube in the left hand and remove the cap.
Like so. Then we pick up a toothbrush,
and we squeeze some of the Salvodent ...
... along the bristles, like so. Then, I want
you to observe, ladies and gentlemen ...
- ... that the young gentleman’s teeth are very dirty.
- They are not.
Yes they are. Now come on, open your mouth.
That’s a good boy.
Now we now proceed to use the brush.
Now with your ordinary commercial dentrifices,
what happens. It is either too gritty ...
... and takes all the enamel off, or it ain’t
and it don’t take nothing off.
But with Salvodent, that’s the happy medium.
Neither too strong, nor too weak.
It performs the functions that nature forgot.
It cleanses the teeth, refreshes the mouth
and removes all traces of halitosis.
- Hali ... what?
- Bad breath, to you sir.
- Same to you
- Thank you, I don’t need it.
Come on. There you are, now.
Now ladies and gentlemen, you will observe
that I have unfortunately disarrayed ...
... the young gentleman’s hair. But that
is easily attended to.
Now I have here, a bottle of Glosswell.
A shilling for that size.
But I have a large size four times the size,
which is only 18 pence.
I will now give you a demonstration
of how it’s used.
You put it on the hair like that, see.
It’s a remarkable substance, which is guaranteed
to give the appearance ...
... of patent leather to the human thatch.
You are now groomed for stardom as they say.
Go on, buzz off you little basket.
What do you want?
Go on hop it!
Stand around for the Lord Mayor’s show!
Hey, where are you going?  Go on back to your place!
Go on. Go on. Go on.
Go on son, step right back.
Here they come.
I say, do you think, we’ll get to
Piccadilly Circus by 1:30?
Yes, 1:30 in the morning.
You got to meet a young lady there?
Here, you can’t bring those there in a
public vehicle. They’re films, ain’t they?
- Yes.
- Then they’re flammable. Go on hop off, big boy.
I’ve got to get to Piccadilly. Can’t I
leave them out on the platform or somewhere?
Ah, it’s “Bartholomew the Strangler”.
Oh well, if it’s you Bartholomew, old ...
... fellow you can stay as long as you promise not
to set about me or any of the passengers.
Thank you.
Well, now everything seems to be alright.
Would you have your drink after all?
No thanks.
Come in.
Oh, excuse me. Will you ring up Whitehall 1212?
May I use your phone?
Put me through to Superintendent Talbot, please.
Spencer here, sir.
A whole busload of people have been
blown up in the West End.
- How awful.
- What time?
Why do you ask?
Well, after all I can’t be in two places
at the same time, can I?
I suppose not.
I may be back later on.
- Got on to anything?
- I am not sure.
Well, make up your mind.
What is it anyway?
Bartho ... Bartholomew something.
Well, that’s a film tin isn’t it?
I thought you said Verloc hadn’t been out
since this morning.
- He hadn’t.
- Well, you best go back there and ...
- ... see if that’s one of their films.
- You want me, sir?
Yes yes. You better join Hollingshead
at the bird shop.
- Yes sir.
- Don’t go inside. Just keep your eyes open.
- Aye aye, sir.
- Alright, Spencer, cut off.
Is that anything to do with it, Mr Spencer?
“Bartholomew the Strangler”.
That’s a film tin, isn’t it?
No. Sardines.
Late extra news! Street bomb sensation!
He’s all right. He can take care of himself.
You’ve got nothing to worry about.
Late extra news! Street bomb sensation!
Big bomb sensation.
- Give me a penny.
- Late extra news! Street bomb sensation!
Late extra news! Late extra news!
Street bomb sensation!
- Look at that.
- Look, the lady’s fainted
I want Mr Verloc.
I want to see Mr Verloc.
I didn’t mean any harm to come to the boy.
Come on, we’ve got to think of tomorrow.
You’ll need all your wits about you,
if they get on to me.
You must answer a fellow.
Do be reasonable.
What would it have been if you had lost me?
That swine in the aquarium ...
... silly jeering dangerous brute
with no more sense than ...
You didn’t know.
Quite right too.
I’m not the chap to worry a woman ...
... that’s fond of me.
You have no business to know.
You’ll have to pull yourself together, my dear.
What’s done can’t be undone.
You go to bed now.
What you want is a good cry.
I know how you feel.
Do you think it doesn’t touch me?
Do you think I fixed it so that he’d be killed?
No, but I’ll tell you who did: ...
... your Scotland Yard friend from next door, Ted.
Blame him.
I’d have carried the thing myself, but
he was hanging around watching, spying.
I couldn’t get away.
Look now ... come now ...
And there’s the future ...
Perhaps ... I don’t know ... perhaps if we ...
... had a kid of our own.
[Movie] Who killed Cock Robin?
I’ve fixed the stuff.
Young Stevie ain’t into that leg problem.
Well, I’m getting along now.
[Movie] Who who who who whooo killed Cock Robin?
[Movie] Who killed Cock Robin?
[Movie] Who got him with a shot and put him on the spot?
Pull yourself together a bit.
That’s better.
Never green.
Why can’t that woman cook green stuff any better?
Surely she’s been long enough here to know
how fond I am of that sort of thing.
I don’t think I want any cabbage.
Couldn’t we send next door for some ...
Ah, don’t!
Stevie! Stevie!
Okay.
- You heard?
- Yes.
I’m terribly sorry.
I do not know what to say.
- You know why I’m here.
- Yes.
I have to arrest him.
Yes
I’ll help him if I can, of course.
For your sake, if not for his.
I’d do anything for you.
You know that don’t you.
Very good of you, Ted.
There isn’t anything you can do for either of us.
Things aren’t as bad as that.
The evidence is against him, I admit.
But nothing’s going to happen to you.
I know this isn’t a very good time to tell you.
I shouldn’t tell you at all, I suppose ...
... but before I take him along
I want you to know that ...
... what happens to you means to a lot me.
I didn’t want to see you hurt but there it is.
I guess I better get my coat if we’re going.
I can’t stop shivering.
- For God’s sake, what happened?
- He killed Stevie.
- I feel warmer now. Let’s go.
- Go where?
- To the police, of course.
- No.  Hold on!  Wait a minute.
Do you realise what this means to you?
- Listen to me. You can’t go through with this.
- Ted, let me go.
You’re not guilty. I know it was an accident.
Anyway, you’re only going to hang yourself for it.
- Please, let me go.
- I know the facts and no one else does.
What chance would you stand with a judge and jury?
I don’t care anymore.
You’re telling me you’ve nothing more to live for.
Is that it?
Look at me.
- Ted!
- My dear, we’re going to get out of all this. Clear out.
- No. It’s no good. You’d just ruin yourself.
- Oh, to hell with that!
It’s Saturday night. We don’t need passports
for the continent if we ask for weekend tickets.
The train leaves at 9:00.
Would someone try and get in that room?
Mrs Jones or anyone?
Mrs Jones comes in at 8 o’clock in the morning.
8 o’clock, and you say we’ve got no chance.
Why we’ve 12 hours start,
Before anyone can find him.
You shut up.
I don’t want to hear another word from you.
Now, go straight to that cinema and bring that birdcage
right back before the police get there and find it.
How could you be so mad as to do such a thing?
- A birdcage with a bomb in it.
- My dear, I couldn’t help ...
Well, you can help now.
Here’s your hat and your coat.
- My dear, but what of the risk ...
- Risk?  Who to?  You?
What about me and the child?
Haven’t our lives been one long risk for months?
Now go on. Get into that taxi.
And get that birdcage!
Bijou Cinema, Penfork Road.
Follow that taxi.
Put this through the Yard.
- Police van ... what’s our number?
- UDC4768.
Reporting: the man under observation
just left the shop ...
... and is making to the Bijou cinema
in a taxi, which we are following.
Any instructions?
Reply is: “Arrest man and Verloc on arrival
at cinema.
Chief Inspector coming from Yard.”
- I’m alright now. I just ...
- You mustn’t look as though you’ve been crying.
- I’m alright.
- Come on.
Ted.
Whatever happens ...
Is Mr Verloc in?
What is that?
- Police.
- Come on.     - Not that way.
- Are you in charge?
- Sorry, no time now, madam.
- But I’m Mrs Verloc.
- Oh! Where have you been, Spencer?
- Look here, sir ...
- He was just taking me along to the police station.
Oh. Oh I see. Does Mrs Verloc know we want
to question her?
Yes, he’s explained all that.
I told him I wanted to make a statement.
- Statement, eh?  What kind of statement?
- Mrs Verloc, you can make your ...
... statement later at the station.
Alright Spencer, I’m in charge of this.
Is the statement to do with your husband?
- Your man’s gone through to the back, sir.
- Right, I’m coming over.
You wait here. Your husband will be along
in a minute.
- It’s no ...
- But Mrs Verloc.
Yes, no time now, I’m afraid. Later.
You stay by the car, Spencer.
How many men have gone round the back?
Mr Verloc?
- Mr Verloc.
- Come on then, boy. Open up.
- It would save a lot of trouble.
- You open that door, I’ll blow the place sky high.
- Perhaps he’s got a bomb.
- Half a tick, better clear the cinema.
- I’ll look after the old man.
- No, you ain’t I’m staying here.
- You’ve got a wife.
- All the more reason why I should stop.
Ha Ha. Go on – get the audience out.
He’s gone to the back. He’s got a bomb.
Says he’s going to use it.
- Bomb? Is Verloc inside too?
- I don’t know. Perhaps something’s happened to him.
Ladies and gentlemen, I must ask you all
to leave the cinema ...
- Mrs Verloc, is your husband inside there?
- She knows nothing.
- Why do you keep interfering, Spencer?
- Yes, he’s inside.
The old man’s got a bomb. What’s your husband’s nerve?
Can he control him?
- No.
- He can’t?
He’s dead!
The roof’s gone.
The whole of the back of the place, clean blown up.
- Anybody ...
- All the audience was clear, thank goodness.
God, I saw some things in the war, but ...
- Is there enough left to identify?
- I wouldn’t say so. No.
You’d better get a First Aid man
to attend to that head of yours.
Spencer.
You’d better look after Mrs Verloc.
Her husband’s dead. Blown to glory.
You can break it to her.
There’ll be a few enquiries later.
There’s nothing against her, so far as I can gather.
Yes, sir.
- Make way there.
- That’s queer.
Is that girl psychic?
She said that Verloc was ...
Dead sir?  You don’t need second sight
in a case like this.
But she said it before.
Or was it after?
I can't remember.